[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
steps to create and working tosca
commander users
working with groups in
process to disable the users
the entire explanation will be done
through hands-on demonstration
now i will explain the detailed steps
for create tosca user
set password by admin
user assignment to admin group and
change password by
user all right
let us start the demo
[Music]
first select the tosca workspace root
directory
and check out
then click on management tab to open
user management section the right
section of the tosca commander window
contains the users and group
by default admin and all users groups
are available
right click on all users and click on
create user icon to create a new user
the new entry represents the username
rename it accordingly
here we are creating the user with name
test
enable field should be checked by
default
level represents the user proficiency
which has three values basic advance and
expert
after creation user has the empty
password
so it's advisable to set the password
right click on user and choose the set
password option
then enter and confirm the new password
[Music]
this option is only available for admin
user
to provide the admin access to the newly
created user we need to drag and drop it
into admins group
though the user instance exists in both
the groups
if we change in one place same will
reflect into all the instances
the password set option is available
here for the admin user only
which means an admin can set or change
the password of any users through this
option
now save the workspace
[Music]
click on check in all icon to save the
newly created user information into
repository
we will check the user now
first close the workspace
closing of workspace will take couple of
seconds
[Music]
after user creation we can access the
workspace using new user after
performing the update all for existing
or need to create new workspace using
the shared repository
now reopen the workspace from here
[Music]
again it will takes couple of seconds to
appease the user prompt
[Music]
once the prompt appears we need to enter
the new test user details and click on
login button
[Music]
the user credential is case sensitive
so we will re-enter the user details
properly
after validating the credential tosca
will open the workspace for the test
user with default view
we will open the project component and
check out the root directory
[Music]
now the logged-in user can change the
password by right clicking on root
directory and selecting the change my
password option
to change the password we need to enter
the old password first and click on ok
button
[Music]
now we will enter new password for the
test user
[Music]
we need to enter the new password again
to confirm it
[Music]
the password is now successfully changed
check in the workspace to update the
repository
the changed password can be used from
the next time
[Music]
now i will explain the detailed steps
for create group
assign user to group
grant access to group and
disable user
let us start the demo
[Music]
first check out the project root
directory
[Music]
right click on top of the user
management section and select the create
user group option to create the new
group
rename the new group based on our choice
to assign users into this group we need
to drag and drop any existing users here
let us drag the new test user
now we will grant access to this group
in any components such as modules
we will check out the modules first
open the property section of the modules
component
now navigate to the owning group
property drop down from the property
section select the newly created group
from here
this will grant the access on modules
components to the new group and the
users associated with it
[Music]
similarly we can grant the access to
other components as well
[Music]
now we will understand how to disable
the user
navigate to user management section and
select the user
to disable the user we need to uncheck
the enable checkbox for this user
same change is replicated to other
instances as well
[Music]
dot perform check in all to update the
changes in shared repository
we will now close the workspace and
reopen it
[Music]
once the user popup appears we will try
login with the credential for the test
user
[Music]
it's not allowing as the user is already
disabled through admin login
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca user management
please stay tuned for more interesting
videos on tosca
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query